

Emma A Holland

FULL-STACK WEB ENGINEER

https://www.linkedin.com/in/emma-holland-492b66232/



https://emmaholland.ca

Phone

+16136614653

Email

emmaholland13@hotmail.com

Location

Belleville, Canada

About me

I'm a passionate developer with 5+ years of industry experience. I specialize in MERN(MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack applications. I'm very adept at third-party integrations and learning new skills fast and effectively. I work well both independently and with large teams of developers. I love collaboration and inclusive design. I'm a 2SLGBTQIA+ ally and when I'm not working I like to volunteer at my local pride center.

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Nucleo Digital Inc.

2022 - Present | Toronto, Canada

Act as a full-stack developer for the squad using node.js and javascript, angular, react.js, and docker for development and system integration requirements.

- Run code reviews, monitor test reports, and ensure code quality
- Ensure all code delivered aligns to CCT/RBC best practices
- · Promote an agile culture and Engineering Mindset way of working inside of the squad and help the designated scrum master run agile events.
- · Analyze, define and document requirements for data, workflow, logical processes, hardware, and operating system environment, interface with other systems, internal and external checks, controls, and outputs
- Provide cost and time estimates for assigned work packages to support the development of timetables and project plans
- · Coordinate coding, testing, implementation, integration, and documentation of solution
- Participate and provide inputs in design discussions with the tech lead and architecture teams.

Senior Software Engineer, Awareness Athletics Inc.

2018 - 2022 | Belleville, Canada

At Awareness Athletics Inc. I was reasonable for overseeing their 'Slo-Pitch For Awareness' brand website. I managed everything from UX/UI design and prototyping to the development of the front-end Design and backend integrations. At Awareness Athletics we used technologies like React, Node, MongoDB, Git, and more to accomplish our desired outcome. Clean and easy-to-use event management and eCommerce platform for their customers.

Education

Harvard University

2022 - Present

Computer Science

Currently, Completing my graduate degree at Harvard University Extension School.

Skills Languages

Third Party Integration | Node.js | Mobile Application Development | Computer Science |
User Experience Design | Software Design | Web Development | Data Modeling |
JavaScript | Backend Development | Database Management Systems | React.js |
User Experience Design | Three Js | UI/UX

English (Native)